simplyhired.co.in 2017-06-06

# Privacy | Simply Hired

## Protect Your Privacy and Safety

Effective Date: June 30, 2016

This Privacy Policy was last updated: June 30, 2016

**THIS IS A NEW PRIVACY POLICY, WHICH IS IN EFFECT AS OF JUNE 30, 2016. BY USING THE SITE, YOU ACCEPT THESE NEW TERMS.**

Simply Hired (“SH Inc.” or "Simply Hired") has drafted its Privacy Policy to ensure that you can clearly understand our data and security practices and policies as you use Simply Hired's websites, apps and mobile services (the "Sites"). This Privacy Policy describes the types of Personal Information we collect, how we use the information, with whom we share it, and the choices you can make about our collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information. The phrase "Personal Information" refers to information that personally identifies you, such as your name, address, telephone number, email address, credit card number or other billing information. We also describe the measures we take to protect the security of your Personal Information and how you can contact us about our privacy practices.

This Privacy Policy incorporates by reference the [Terms Of Use](http://www.simplyhired.com/about/terms-of-service) for the Sites, which apply to this Privacy Policy. When you visit the Sites or provide us with information, you consent to our use and disclosure of the information we collect or receive, as described in this Privacy Policy, unless separate terms are offered by you in writing and accepted in writing by Simply Hired.

Please review this Privacy Policy periodically, as we may update it from time to time without prior notice to reflect changes in our data practices. We will post a notice on our Sites to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Policy and will indicate when it was most recently updated.

## Information We Collect

In addition to collecting information about you when you use our Sites, we may also obtain information about you from our business partners, other third parties and publicly available information.

The types of information we may obtain include: 

  * Your Personal Information, if you choose to provide it or if we obtain it in the manner described above. Please note that you are not required to provide us with any Personal Information in order to perform job searches or to read the content portions of the Sites. If you wish to receive an email job alert, you must provide an email address. Please note that if you provided the Simply Hired Site with Personal Information prior to June 30, 2016, this Personal Information will no longer be retrievable on line, and you should contact Simply Hired at help @ simplyhired.com (please remove spaces when sending email) to have this Personal Information deleted. If you do not wish to continue to receive job alerts, please unsubscribe by pressing the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any job alert sent beginning on June 30, 2016 and after. Your email address sent previously to the Sites may continue to be used to send you job alerts unless you choose to unsubscribe.
  * Your demographic information (such as ZIP or postal code, occupation, education, experience, age, gender and race or ethnicity). We collect this information either through the registration process, from your resume or in the manner described above.
  * Job search behavior and preferences and a record of the searches that you make on our Sites. We do this in order to present you with recommendations based on your interests as expressed previously through your activities on our Sites.
  * Other details that you may submit to us or that may be included in the information provided to us by third parties.

We may collect information stored in your social media profile that you authorize us to access when you use your social media profile to invoke features on the Sites. Simply Hired provides software applications ("Apps") available to the public. If you decide to download one of our Apps, we may collect your profile information, including your social network site user ID, email address, name, city, state, social network site profile image URL, and employment history, including job titles and company names.

## How We Use the Information We Collect

We may use the information we obtain about you to: 

  * Provide products or services you request.
  * Maintain a record of the jobs you view or apply to on our Sites.
  * Inform you of relevant job postings that may be of interest to you.
  * Provide administrative notices or communications applicable to your use of the Sites.
  * Respond to your questions and comments and provide customer support.
  * Contact you and deliver information to you that, in some cases, is targeted to your interests (such as relevant services, educational or other career development opportunities); enable you to communicate with us through our blogs, social networks and other interactive media; and solicit your feedback and input. These communications will contain links for preference management and, where appropriate, unsubscribe links, should you decide you do not want to receive further communications.
  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business and the products and services we offer.
  * Analyze and enhance our marketing communications and strategies (including identification of when emails we have sent to you have been received and read).
  * Analyze trends and statistics regarding visitors' use of our Sites, mobile applications and social media assets, and the jobs viewed or applied to on our Sites.
  * Protect against and prevent fraud, unauthorized transactions, claims and other liabilities, and manage risk exposure, including by identifying potential hackers and other unauthorized users.
  * Enforce our Sites' [Terms Of Use](http://www.simplyhired.com/about/terms-of-service).
  * Comply with applicable legal requirements, industry standards and our policies, including as is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process (including subpoenas, search warrants, court orders) and law enforcement instructions and orders.

We also use non-personally identifiable information and certain technical information about your computer and your access of the Sites (including your IP address) in order to operate, maintain and manage the Sites. We collect this information by automated means, such as cookies and web beacons, as described in more detail below.

If we seek to use the information we obtain about you in other ways, we will provide specific notice and request your consent at the time of collection.

## Information We Share

When you apply for a job through the Sites, employers will have access to information about you and your potential interest in employment opportunities. Those employers may use your information to contact you directly. Additionally, when you apply for a job through a link to a third party found on the Sites, the information supplied by you may be shared with Simply Hired by that third party and also may become part of the employer's database. In these instances, the use of such information by the employer will be subject to the privacy policy of that company, and we are not responsible for that company's use of your information.

The Sites may track the total number of visitors to our Sites, the number of visitors to each page of our Sites, IP addresses, External Web Sites linked to, search terms and the domain names of our users' Internet Service Providers, operating system and browser type, and we may analyze these data for trends and statistics in the aggregate, but such information will be maintained, used and disclosed in aggregate form only and it will not contain personally identifiable information. We also may collect aggregate information such as demographics including age, occupation, gender, salary information and labor statistics. Such aggregate information may be collected from data that you have provided to us via usage of the Sites and/or public records, and is not unique to you nor is it linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. We may use such aggregate information to analyze trends, administer the Sites, track users' movements, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We may share this aggregate information with third parties, including our affiliated and parent companies, for various reasons related to our business to assist them in targeting advertisements to appropriate audiences.

Other than instances in which users opt to provide their Personal Information via a job application, include it in a job posting or otherwise provide permission to share it, we do not sell our users' Personal Information to anyone for any reason. When applying to jobs, our users decide for themselves how much contact information they wish to display.

We share Personal Information with our service providers, including our own affiliated companies and parent company, who help us in the delivery of our own products and services to you. These service providers may only use or disclose the information as necessary to perform services on our behalf or as otherwise required by law.

Simply Hired also may disclose specific user information when we determine, in good faith, that such disclosure is necessary to comply with the law, to cooperate with or seek assistance from law enforcement, to prevent a crime or protect national security, or to protect the interests or safety of Simply Hired or other users of the Sites. This means, for example, that Simply Hired may honor subpoenas, search warrants, law enforcement or court-mandated requests to reveal a user’s electronic address and identity, or other properly requested information.

Personal Information we have collected may be passed on to a third party in the event of a bankruptcy or another corporate reorganization of Simply Hired. In addition, if we are acquired by or merged with another company, or in the event of any sale of assets or other transfer of ownership by Simply Hired to a third party (whether by merger, sale or otherwise), or any other reorganization or joint venture, or assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any of Simply Hired’s business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceeding), the Personal Information we have collected may be transferred to such third party as well as such third party’s affiliates and subsidiaries, and may be used by such third party in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Please note that the Resume and Saved Jobs products are no longer available on the Sites. Any resume or job application you sent to an Employer via a job application may be kept by the Employer, and you should check such Employer’s privacy policy to understand how they keep your Personal Information.

You can direct questions regarding this Privacy Policy to Simply Hired by emailing us at: privacyoffice @ simplyhired.com (please remove spaces when sending email). Please include your name and email address in email requests.

## About Cookies, Tracking Choices, and Third Party Advertisers

### Changes To Our Cookie Policy

From time to time, it may be necessary for us to change this cookie policy. We suggest that you check here periodically for any changes.

By using or accessing the Sites, you are consenting to Simply Hired’s use of Cookies as follows:

“Cookies” are text-only pieces of information that a website transfers to an individual’s hard drive or other website-browsing equipment for record-keeping purposes, and allow the Sites to remember important information that will make your use of Simply Hired more convenient. A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the “lifetime” of the cookie, and a randomly generated unique number or other value. We use cookies for a variety of purposes in order to improve your online experience, for analytics and for marketing, but specifically we use Cookies on the Sites for the following purposes:

a. Your Preferences: We use Cookies to store certain user preferences on the Sites. For example, we may store the recent searches you have performed in a Cookie so that we can allow you to easily repeat those searches when you return to the Sites.

b. Analytical Purposes: We use Cookies to analyze user activity in order to improve the Sites. We can use such analysis to gain insights about how to improve the functionality and user experience of the Sites. Using Cookies, for example, we can look at aggregate patterns like the average number of job searches that users perform.

c. Referral Tracking: We use Cookies to associate user activity with the third party website that referred the user to our Sites, or to associate user activity that Simply Hired referred to a third party website. These third party partner websites receive credit for the activity of users they refer to our Sites, or give Simply Hired credit for the activity of users referred to such third party websites.

d. Marketing: We use Cookies from third-party partners, which allow us to display Simply Hired promotional material to you on other sites you visit across the Internet.

When we use cookies to track the total number of visitors to our Sites, this is done on an anonymous aggregate basis (as cookies do not in themselves carry any personal data). We may also employ cookies so that we remember your computer when it is used to return to the Sites to help customize your Simply Hired web experience. We may associate personal information with a cookie file in those instances. Use the options in your web browser if you do not wish to receive a cookie or if you wish to set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. You can easily delete any cookies that have been installed in the cookie folder of your browser. Check your browser’s cookie settings support pages for instructions on how to enable and disable cookies for various browsers and the job seeker web beacon. Consult your mobile device documentation for information on how to disable cookies. If you disable all cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all the features of this website.

By clicking on jobs posted on the Sites, you may receive a third party job seeker web beacon. If you would like to remove yourself from this third party job seeker web beacon, you must [click here](https://conv.indeed.com/pagead/conversion-optout). Users should also be aware that third parties may provide employers with code to place on its website that pings the job seeker web beacon and tracks whenever a job seeker has applied to a job on that employer’s website. This information may be provided to Simply Hired; however, Simply Hired does not and cannot collect any of the job seeker’s personally identifiable information and does not have access to the cookies in the employer’s domain. At most, Simply Hired may be notified that a job seeker has applied. If a jobseeker has disabled the web beacon, the code provided to the employer will have no functionality.

Simply Hired may use the AdWords and Remarketing Lists features of Google Analytics for Display Advertisers. Simply Hired and Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on your past visits to our Sites. This means that vendors including Google may display Simply Hired promotional material on other sites you visit across the Internet.

You may opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertisers including AdWords and opt-out of customized Google Display Network ads by visiting the Google Ads Preferences Manager. To provide website visitors more choice on how their data is collected by Google Analytics, Google has developed an Opt-out Browser add-on, which is available by visiting Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on, to enable you to opt-out of Google’s programs.

**Simply Hired marketing service providers.** If you do not want Simply Hired and its marketing services providers to follow your usage of our services via cookies and web beacons, and to learn more about these providers and their privacy policies, please visit the website for each of the third parties below: 

  * Facebook
  * Twitter
  * Nielsen
  * Yandex (Russia only)
  * Optimizely
  * Sift Science
  * Olark
  * Demandbase
  * Perfect Audience
  * Zendesk
  * Appsflyer
  * MediaCom
  * Mixpanel
  * Sizmek
  * Heap Analytics
  * Marketo
  * comScore

Opting out of these services does not mean you will no longer receive online advertising. It does mean that the service from which you opted out will no longer deliver ads tailored to your use. Simply Hired may update this list periodically to include other marketing services providers.

## International Data Transfers

We are a United States company. When you use the Sites, you are voluntarily reaching into the United States to do business. That is your choice. When we obtain Personal Information about you, we will process and store the information outside of the country in which you are located, including in the United States. The U.S. or the countries in which we process the information may not have data protection laws that offer equivalent protection for your information as the country in which you are located. Further, users who access your information, such as potential employers, also may be located in a different country than you and different laws may apply to their use of your information. By accessing or registering with the Sites you consent to the use, disclosure and transfer of information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and subject to the laws of the United States. If you do not agree to have your data processed in the United States or other countries outside of your home country, do not use the Sites.

## How We Protect Personal Information

Simply Hired maintains administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to assist us in protecting the Personal Information we collect against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized disclosure or use or alteration. However NO SITE CAN BE MADE PERFECTLY SAFE. If you are not willing to proceed on those grounds please do not use the Sites.

We have implemented technical and organizational security measures to protect your information from misuse, unauthorized or unlawful access or disclosure, loss, alteration, damage or destruction. These measures include: 

  * Physical safeguards that include storing data in areas with controlled access.
  * Technology safeguards that include using anti-virus and endpoint protection software encryption, and monitoring of our systems and data centers to ensure that they comply with our security policies.
  * Organizational safeguards that include training on security and privacy, to make sure our employees and contractors understand the importance and means by which they must protect your information. Our organizational privacy policies and standards also guide our handling of your information.

Please note that the information we collect from you may be stored on servers in the United States and anywhere Simply Hired, our third party affiliates or parent company, or our vendors operate. By accessing and registering with the Sites you consent to the use, disclosure and transfer of information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and subject to the laws of the United States.

## Links to Other Websites

Our Sites may contain links to other websites that are owned or operated by other companies, including but not limited to affiliated third party entities. If you choose to visit any linked websites, we encourage you to review their privacy statements carefully, as they may differ from ours. We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of websites that are owned by companies outside of Simply Hired’s affiliate and parent companies.

Our Sites may also link to co-branded websites that are maintained by Simply Hired and one or more of our business partners or third party affiliates who are collecting your Personal Information pursuant to their own privacy practices. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on any co-branded site to which you link for information on the privacy practices of that site.

Please note that no electronic transmission of information can be entirely secure. We cannot guarantee that the security measures we have in place to safeguard Personal Information will never be defeated or fail, or that those measures will always be sufficient or effective. Therefore, although we are committed to protecting your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your Personal Information will always remain private. As a user of the Sites, you understand and agree that you assume all responsibility and risk for your use of the Sites and the internet generally, the documents you post or access and for your conduct on and off the Sites.

## California, USA Residents

California law permits its residents to, once per calendar year, request and receive information about a business' disclosure of certain categories of Personal Information to other companies for direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and a user of any of the Sites, you can request a copy of this information from Simply Hired by sending an email to privacyoffice @ simplyhired.com (eliminate spaces when sending email). Please include your name and email address in email requests.

## Children's Privacy

The Sites are not directed to individuals under the age of fourteen (14), but if you are under the age of 18 or the age of majority in your jurisdiction, you must use Simply Hired under the supervision of a parent or legal guardian, or responsible adult. Simply Hired does not knowingly collect or solicit information from anyone under the age of 14. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 14, we will delete that information as quickly as possible.
